<!-- This file defines the attributes that are shared between the 
     Selector subclasses. --> 

    &binding-attrs;

    <attribute>
      <description><![CDATA[<![CDATA[
	Set this attribute to true when the web application needs to
        see what the currently selected value of the component is, but
        must not be allowed to make any changes to the 
	model object property associated with the component. 
        If true, the value of the component is
        rendered as text (using the <code>statictext</code>
        component). If there are multiple selections, the string
        representation of each selection is separated by a space. 
        The text is preceded by a label if the <code>label</code>
        attribute was set, or if a <code>label</code>facet was
        specified. ]]>
      ]]></description>
      <attribute-name>readonly</attribute-name>
    </attribute>

 
    <attribute>
      <description>
      Sets the tooltip for the component. This will be
      renderered as the HTML title attribute. 
      </description>
      <attribute-name>toolTip</attribute-name>
    </attribute>

    <attribute>
    <description><![CDATA[This attribute, if set, causes a label to be
      rendered with the component (see also the labelLevel
      attribute). If specified, a HTML <code>label</code> element is
      generated  adjacent to the <code>select</code> element
      (equivalent to using the label component). This attribute is
    ignored if a <code>label</code> facet has been specified.]]>
    </description>
    <attribute-name>label</attribute-name>
    </attribute>

    <attribute>
      <description><![CDATA[
      Associates this component with a converter. The role of the
      converter is to convert the values of the
      <code>Selection</code>s and the selected Object(s) to and from
      String representations. The value of this attribute must be an
      EL expression that is a reference to a
      <code>javax.faces.converter.Converter</code>. ]]>
      </description>
      <attribute-name>converter</attribute-name>
    </attribute>

    <attribute>
      <description>
      The value of this attribute must be a single character. When the
      corresponding key is pressed, focus is transferred to this
      component. If the label attribute has been specified, the
      accesskey is also set on the generated label. 
      </description>
      <attribute-name>accesskey</attribute-name>
    </attribute>

