<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<renderer>
  <description><![CDATA[


<code></code>Use
the <code>ui:image</code>
tag to display an inline image in the rendered
HTML page. The url attribute is used to specify the URL to the image
file that
is to be displayed.&nbsp;&nbsp; If you use an image that is a
PNG type and ends with ".png " this tag will output the correct format
for an &lt;img&gt; tag to display a PNG correctly in Internet
Explorer.&nbsp; In order to use this feature you must set the
height and width properties of this tag..<br>
<br>
The <code>ui:image</code>
tag can be used to display a theme-specific image in the
rendered HTML page. The icon attribute used in the <code>ui:image
</code>tag is
a key value that is mapped to a URL in theme properties file. The key
is used
to look up the appropriate image source and related attributes from the
current
theme. By specifying a key, you avoid the need to specify predefined
constants
such as height and width. The image can also be seamlessly changed when
a
different theme is selected.<br>
<br>
Note: currently the list of
icons that you can use is not publicly
supported, but the icon names are specified in the
<code>/com/sun/rave/web/ui/suntheme/SunTheme.properties</code>
file. The names are
listed as resource keys of the format <code>image.ICON_NAME</code>.
Use only
the part of the key that follows image. For example, if the key is
<code>image.ALARM_CRITICAL_SMALL</code>,
you should specify
<code>ALARM_CRITICAL_SMALL</code>
as the value of the icon attribute of the
<code>ui:icon</code>
tag. A list of supported icon values will be published in
the near future.<br>
<h3>HTML Elements and Layout</h3>
The rendered HTML page displays an XHTML compliant <code>&lt;img&gt;</code>
element with any applicable element attributes. The attributes can be
specified
through the <code>&lt;ui:image&gt;</code>
tag attributes.
<h3>Client Side Javascript
Functions</h3>
None.
<br>
<h3>Examples</h3>
<h4>Example 1: Create an image</h4>
<code>&lt;ui:image id="image1"
url="../images/dot.gif" /&gt;
<br>
<br>
</code>This will generate the
following markup: <br>
&nbsp;&nbsp; <br>
<code>&lt;img
src="../images/dot.gif" alt="" /&gt;
</code><br>
<br>
<h4>Example 2: Create a theme
specific image<br>
</h4>
<code>&lt;ui:image id="image2"
icon="</code><code>ALARM_CRITICAL_SMALL</code><code>"
/&gt;
</code>


	

      ]]></description>

  <component-family>com.sun.rave.web.ui.Image</component-family>

  <renderer-type>com.sun.rave.web.ui.Image</renderer-type>

  <attribute>
    <attribute-name>value</attribute-name>
    <attribute-extension>
      <is-hidden>true</is-hidden>
      <tag-attribute>false</tag-attribute>
    </attribute-extension>
  </attribute>

  &visible-attrs;

  <renderer-extension>
    <tag-name>image</tag-name>
    <taglib-prefix>ui</taglib-prefix>
    <taglib-uri>http://www.sun.com/web/ui</taglib-uri>
  </renderer-extension>

</renderer>
